This is my kitchen table and also my
filing system.
Over much of the past three decades,
I've been an investor the highest
calling of mankind I've often thought
was private equity.
And then I started interviewing.
Oh, I watch your interviews because I
know how to do something.
I've learned in doing my interviews how
leaders make it to the top.
I asked him how much you wanted.
He said to 50.
I said, Fine.
I didn't negotiate with him.
I didn't know due diligence.
I have something I'd like to sell and
how they stay there.
You don't feel inadequate now because
being only the second wealthiest man in
the world, Is that right?
In 2015, Nick Skowronski started a small
company designed to help people with
their foreign currency exchanges.
Today, that company is Revolut.
It is the most valuable pre-IPO company
in all of Europe.
I had a chance recently in Washington,
D.C., to sit down with Nixon Trotsky to
talk about his amazing story, how he
grew a very small company into such a
giant financial behemoth.
Let's talk about Rebel Loot, because
it's a company that's based in
U.K.
focused more on Europe than the United
States.
And we'll get to that in a moment.
But let's talk about what it does for
the American audience, for example.
What is rebel loot?
What does it actually do?
Well, roll it as a digital bank.
So we provide global banking services
for our people in more than 40
countries.
So everything is packed into one simple
up.
So you can get banking, you can do
wealth management, stock trading,
savings bonds, crypto can borrow money.
And you also have lifestyle service, for
example, that can get your self esteem.
It can earn a book allowance.
You can book a hotel and so on.
So everything is in one up for your
financial services.
Do you have a partner to start it with?
I actually started a loan, so I build a
product.
I hired a team
then while infrastructure that I hired
so late that made him I think it was
till 78.
I met him co-founder as well, because it
was easier for him to kind of, you know,
recruit engineers if he had title
co-founder.
So you start the company and the mission
you had was to enable people to do what
that they couldn't do.
What was your purpose in starting the
company?
So I was a trader back then.
I learned
very quick in calculating numbers in my
head.
And then every time when I went abroad
or when I send money, I could calculate
like I was here, $10, $50 and so on.
And my initial idea was to build a
product is simple, up with a card
attached to it that allows you to spend
money anywhere in the world at
inter-bank rate.
So saving effectively 50 to $70 and
every $1,000 that you spent.
In other words, you weren't trying to
convert people's currency, you were
letting them have a card that would
enable them to buy something in whatever
currency they wanted.
Yeah.
So it's both right.
You can exchange currency or you can buy
directly from your existing currency.
And normally throughout Europe, when you
go to Europe, you see everywhere
currency exchange places, and they
always charge a fee.
I don't remember what it is, six, 7%.
So you decided to start a currency
exchange business without charging a
fee?
Well, you can call currency exchange
business interbank credit without
charging a fee, Correct.
You didn't go out and build a physical
bank.
You did it all online.
Is that right?
Exactly.
So how did you get people to know about
this service?
Did you start advertising online for
anything?
We didn't spend any single marketing for
the first 5 to 7 years of our being in
operation.
So it was all word of mouth.
So I remember when I finally launched
the product, it was summer 2015, and I
physically was selling my product to
friends, family,
even people I don't know.
Okay, So if I go to London today and I
say, Here's $10 and I want to exchange
it on a regular place, and I would get
back pounds minus about a six or 7%, 8%
fee.
Correct.
So if I went on your service,
what would I get back?
And I would I get back everything for a
essentially no fee.
Exactly.
Then you make the money in effect on the
float because you're getting paid by
somebody and then you kind of can invest
that money and then you don't have to
pay somebody for a while.
Is that how you make the money?
So then when you spent with the card,
merchant effectively pays the base 2 to
3%?
Yeah.
Okay.
But that's not the customer paying, but
rather a business itself.
Although I want to be clear that it was
initial product in 2015.
Now, especially for US customers, we are
fully licensed digital bank providing
all the of services.
You have a
European banking license now, is that
right?
So we have a European bank, so we are
regulated by European Central Bank.
We have a UK bank, a license regulated
by PRA.
Then we also have multiple other
licences, for example, Mexico, Colombia,
tourism.
And you're now applying for a US banking
licence.
Correct.
How long does it take to get a US
banking licence?
Right now should take us up to 12
months.
But again, it depends.
So official target is four months.
Well, there are multiple steps involved.
It can be longer.
Are you
confident that you can get a banking
license in the United States, or do you
think you'll get it?
I think it's obviously much easier for
us and the other administration, plus
that we have so many other banking
licenses.
Plus, we have a medical center.
So for us, it became much easier
compared to two years ago.
Do you have a credit card business as
well?
Yeah, we have credit cards in several
markets.
Yes.
Is that and you have credit cards and
debit cards.
We have debit cards in every single
market.
Credit cards, I think in five or six
markets.
So in Europe, we have 20% penetration.
So one out of five adults in Europe,
they use.
Robert.
It calls and then I said, Don't like us.
We have much higher penetration.
For example, in Ireland we have four out
of five adults using Revolut.
So younger people seem to like things
that are called cryptocurrencies.
Are you involved in cryptocurrencies?
Do you trade cryptocurrencies or make
markets for people?
So as a business, we have a pretty large
crypto currency business.
I think we the largest we have the
largest crypto business in Europe with
our volumes.
Personally, I don't speculate crypto,
but I use it sometimes for transfers.
So in the United States, what do you
hope to be able to do with your banking
license if you get it?
What is the market gap that you think
you can fill that maybe others aren't
doing?
So basically I mentioned already our
retail business.
So it's one simple up where you can do
everything, everything what you need for
your financial life and the second
direction.
We also provide the business accounts
for businesses and again, end to end
services that you need to run your
business.
So payments, banking credit will come as
well.
Wealth Management or Treasury, we'll
call the Treasury about acquiring as
well.
So for example, or a North American
company I'll need to start.
So strive for acquiring then JPMorgan
for my business, banking on something
else for plus something else for
payroll.
So we provide all the services in one
product.
While if you conquer the U.S.
the way you've conquered the UK and
Europe, is China next or you're you're
not going to focus on that.
Asia where they've been focusing.
So spending a lot of time studying Asia.
And then as a search, we applied for
multiple banking license in Asia as
well, and then some more than what we've
got already around, like China is on the
list as well.
And our one day I hope we can set up our
business there.
Now, some people have written that your
bank Revolut is worth $75 billion.
Have you ever thought of taking your
organization public?
Well, the way I think about it, we kind
of will be ready probably in two years
time.
But then again, depends on how good the
market is.
Since you don't have an IPO, how do the
people who work for you make some money?
You make a market for people to sell
their shares internally.
Yeah.
So we do secondaries every one or two
years.
One, people can sell a certain portion
of their stocks to investors.
So you've done secondary sales for your
employees, so employees can then get
some liquidity.
Do you expect before you go public
you'll do any more of those or you just
want to wait to go public before you
liquify any more stock?
Yeah, I think so.
We might do second thoughts as well
before we do IPO because we do it every
one or two years.
So we made the second order as well.
All right.
Well, if anybody wants to sell their
shares to me, let me know.
And have any investment bankers told you
why they're the best to do the IPO for
you?
Yeah.
Obviously, every single one is the best.
Everyone is the best.
You're not in a rush to do it.
You don't need the money.
So we're bank.
And then for the bank, it's super
important to have trust.
And then the public companies are
trusted more compared to private
companies.
So there's a reason.
What are you most proud of having done
so far, and what do you most enjoy?
Well, it's basically designing
something, designing solutions to solve
a problem that I see are being realised
and I'm using it.
That's what I enjoy when I see some
elegant solution.
Many people think that companies like
yours, which are often called fintech
companies, financial technology
companies are changing the world
dramatically, but they could be changed
dramatically.
So, for example, artificial intelligence
is coming along.
Are you worried about artificial
intelligence or do you use artificial
intelligence to help grow your company?
Well, this additional tool that we
obviously use and the thing with alarm
bells.
So it's another AR surface on top of the
infrastructure that we build because our
banking is not the simple operate on the
app.
You have a lot of background, a lot of
systems in a lot of regulatory systems
and so on.
An app is a fairly interface to all this
backend logic and then allow them can be
something on top of the app or directly
interacting with our back end logic to
call it another interface.
That's what we're building as well,
allowing people to interact with all our
products through channel.
Let's talk about how you came to start
the company.
So you are starting.
Doesn't sound like you're a native of
England from your accent, originally
from Russia.
So it came to UK first in 2006 for the
internship, then then 2007, then came
for another internship.
And afterwards I stayed to be employed
by Lehman Brothers as a trader.
And at what age did you leave Russia?
20 years old, I learned as soon as I
finished my university, I moved to
London to work full time for Lehman
Brothers.
And where are your parents educated?
Are they math specialists or do they
have computer training or not?
So my father, he's a physicist by
training.
My mother, she's a teacher.
I assume you are pretty good math
student or a physics student or
something because you have a technology
background, I assume?
Yeah.
I was always trained in the mess physics
as well.
Right.
So you go to England.
And did you have a job lined up before
you got there?
So Lehman Brothers came to my university
and then they tried to recruit some
people for the internship.
So they recruited me for internship.
I came there in summer 2006,
and then they invited Ms.
for a second internship in spring 2000,
so on.
And they also gave me a job offer for
full time when I graduate from my
university.
So when I graduated in July, I think it
was July 2000.
So I came to London to work full time
for Lehman Brothers.
Didn't Lehman go under at some point?
2000 HK So it wasn't then you were you
there then?
Yeah, I was there.
I was one of probably 200 people on the
trading floor where it all happened.
I still remember there was or the Sunday
evening announcement that I was
wondering.
I kept learning to come on Monday
morning to my job.
So I came out.
Then I had all this 200 traders looked
at one trading floor, everything.
All the systems were locked, were all
playing the same game.
I think it was like game shooting
helicopters or something.
All, all different people because there
was nothing to do.
So did you think capitalism wasn't such
a great system at that point?
When you go to Lehman Brothers and they
go bankrupt, then you're out of work?
Yeah, I was full of confidence, all of
self.
I was not afraid to lose the job because
I knew I can always find a new one.
So did you have a hard time finding
another job?
No, I got a kind of job offer from the
more and then from criticism.
All right.
And so where did you go?
I went to crisis, but the rest was
they've had their problems, too,
actually.
Did you leave Credit Suisse before they
had their problems?
Yeah, of course.
I left Credit Suisse 2013.
So basically, as soon as I got my
British passport, I resigned.
And then when I came to UK, it was now a
kind of objective to stay there.
More than two years.
I was wanted to start my own business,
but then I no, I said one year, then the
second, the third year and then after
year six, when I got my passport, I
decided to resign and then start my own
business.
Okay, You started your business in 2015
or so.
Start working until 13 and I launched in
2015.
Did you have any capital to help you
start the company?
I have my own savings, yes.
All right.
So you put in some of your own money,
but you presumably weren't a
multibillionaire, so you didn't put in
that much money.
Right?
I mean, back then I put probably about
or half a million dollars, half a
million overall.
But obviously, I also didn't work for
two years myself.
So if you don't count my salary, I don't
have any salary.
So to to build something bigger than was
a much cheaper compared to nowadays you
have at my venture capital arm as it's
called, quantum light.
So it's a separate business or asset.
It was three years ago.
As entrepreneur, I've done a lot of
fundraising roles for the business and
then I think a certain point of time I
was very pissed off with the
growth.
Thinking.
Mentality, right.
So I have cases where terms were
withdrawn, so contemptuous.
I have cases where around the world
markets are down because of some viewers
down.
So I had the quite quite a lot of
negative experiences overseas.
And then as I found out, I also wanted
to invest my own money.
And I thought I can create something
better in terms of investment there.
I think there has to be a scientific
approach rather than human judgment.
And then we build effective models.
Let's invest in start UPS series, be
based on millions and millions data
points on start ups.
So they're trained machine learning
models that invest.
Plus on top of it, I'm able to share
with these startups my personal
knowledge as a founder.
Plus, we help or startups to distribute
their products for revalued or to sell
into role.
So we're all it's a much better value
proposition to founders compared to with
you.
What would you call you when you're
doing angel investing or around a or we
would do series B We we started we, we
just launched the fund for serious
years.
What do you did you raise money for it I
assume people gave you all the money you
wanted, but did you just use your own
money in your friends money, or did you
have to go out and raise money?
First of all, was $250 million.
So I put around 24% my own money and
then the rest was external.
LPC And what types of rates of return do
you think you get in that fund?
So basically when I had this idea, when
we build a model and then we started
backtesting, the model, it produces
effectively 40 to 50% year on year
returns, long term returns.
So when we started investing based on
the model, I think now we are called top
44% of the funds the world in terms of
returns.
So usually 30 to 40% returns.
So you ever use your credit card and it
gets turned down.
In other words, you go to use a credit
card at a restaurant or somewhere and
they say your credit's the night.
Is that ever happened to you
or initially,
yeah, but it was more than eight, nine
years ago when service was on the stable
now which is don't have declines.
But now, when that happened to you, did
you tell people who you were or you
didn't say, Look, I'm the founder of the
company and you were just calling
ingeniously and trying to find out what
happened, why or why it was declined.
How many customers Revolut have now?
So have 75 million customers.
How big do you think you can take it?
You think you can take it to 100 million
customers or more?
Yeah, we can take it 200 million
customers.
Our internal target is 100 million daily
active customers.
Then 100 million daily active customers
will transfer about 300 million monthly
active.
It is said that companies, if they're
really going to survive and prosper and
for over many years of time, they have
to have a good culture.
What is the culture you're trying to
build in your company?
So we have these five cultural values
pretty well defined, starting with Learn
Never Settle.
So our soul is about being ambitious and
setting up for big goals.
Secondly, it's about the Dream team.
So we prefer to work in a small team of
extremely high intelligence people
rather than in teams of four average
people.
Third one is to get things done is very
important to be
kind of, you know, getting things done
around.
Then we have a cultural principle called
Deliver.
Well, it's about almost perfection in
everything, what we do in terms of
product.
What new worlds do you want to conquer?
You've built a big company, but we're
still scratching the surface in terms of
what is possible in building our first
truly global bank, because now we're in
40 countries who want to be in 100
countries who.
If you look at the future of the
financial service world, do you think
that there's a future for large banks
that keep having these big buildings?
Where do you think ultimately five or
ten or 15 years from now, everybody is
going to be online with everything in
five, ten years?
Then we'll see more and more
consolidation.
I think we'll see more and more sort of
digital champions in the regions taking
on more and more banking shares in those
regions.
So maybe this will take ten years, maybe
it'll take 50 years, 20 years.
But I do think that we'll see less and
less legacy banks or less and less the
legacy banks will make so much money.
So are you enjoying doing all this?
Maybe you enjoy running the bank,
running the venture fund, and doing
interviews with people like me, or are
you having a good time or or you're not
that happy or I mean, certainly like
certain things.
I like certain things I don't like.
So I love building products.
I love solving problems.
I don't like delays,
which can be quite funny in the
regulator business because certain
things can be outside of kind of, you
know, your decision making is what are
the skill sets that you think are
required to build a company like this?
And do you look for those same skill
sets in the people you hire?
Well, you do not need to be good at
trading at all.
For me, when I started, I knew nothing
about banks because I was in Trader
Investment bank.
I was a very different organisation
compared to a retail bank and the
payments company as well.
So I learnt everything from scratch
a skills wise.
What do you have
A thing you're looking to have ambitions
and hunger
plus as a character,
plus a lot of energy because it's pretty
painful, you know, in a lot of ways with
all the problems.
Plus, you always need to have very
strong, logical, logical thinking,
abstract thinking.
You should be good with product as well,
like ability to build something nice and
slick.
We're just looking for ultimately
three things.
First is a high IQ of brains, and then
we have certain ways how to understand
whether a person is smart or not,
whether they are ideological or not
simple one.
Number two is their character, how
ambitious they are, how hungry they are.
And third is their skills for heart
desire.
They need to be good at design and so
on.
What new worlds do you want to conquer?
You've built a big company.
Eventually you might take a public.
You've got a great venture capital firm.
What do you want to do next?
Well, majority of third party digital is
still to revolut, but we're still
scratching the surface in terms of what
is possible in building our first truly
global bank.
Are you worried that somebody who's ten
years younger than you is going to come
along and with a better mousetrap and
beat what you're doing or you're not
worried about that so much?
I mean, really, I think there are
windows of opportunity in the world of
when there are certain tools or
opportunities.
But usually what happens ten, 20 people
jump on this opportunity, as in this
particular country, to do this
particular product and then people
compete.
I think opportunity for fintech.
Thinking the majority of consciousness
is gone now because they're all ready to
play us legacy banks.
They kind of caught up as of all
products.
This is very hard to build anything new
in fintech, or at least I don't see the
procedure.
But nonetheless, I mean, maybe I don't
see and I think maybe there is, you
know, someone smart people can come up
with a better product.
So most of the bankers I know have hair
that's like mine.
It's shorter years, just a little bit
longer.
Is that are your trademark or if you
want to get a banking license, the
United States, you think you need to cut
your hair or not thinking of offering to
wear a suit, whatever.
Do you have friends from high school
that call you up and say, Remember me?
I was your friend in high school or
sometimes friends of friends.
I it's not that hard to get get a hold
of you.
No, no, this is it.
It's easy.
Okay, well, next time I'm in London, I
will call you up and see how he is.
You know, make sure you told me your
number.
So record it.
Otherwise, I don't pick up on numbers.
You're now probably the richest person
in UK or certainly one of them.
What are you going to do with us?
You're going to build
art galleries or museums or give it away
to social causes.
What do you want to do with all this
wealth?
You can't spend $25 billion in your
lifetime.
Probably.
Well, I'm just very focused on business.
Continue to make the best products and
then continue to expand.
And then all this wealth is in the
company, right?
So I do not really to plan.
I don't really plan to sell the company
more than spend all this money.
So I just continue to work on, you know,
what's necessary to.
To to build a first global bank.
Because now when 40 countries want to be
in 100 countries
who.